

BEN KNOLL

- OVERLAND PARK KANSAS
- (816) 277 9623
- BKNOLL66@GMAIL.COM
- BENKNOLL.ME
- GITHUB.COM/GRASSYKNOLL88

EDUCATION

2018
UNIVERSITY OF
KANSAS
Fullstack Web
Development

2015
CENTER FOR
FURNITURE
CRAFTSMANSHIF
Furniture

PROFILE

I am a full stack web developer, with experience in furniture design. As a craftsmen, I have drafted blueprints and implemented manufacturing processes from start to finish, while maintaining the efficiency and versatility demanded by the project at hand. I believe this unique skill-set partnered with the combination of my creativity, detail orientation, and years of customer service will result in great success within the software industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1/2018 - 7/2018 UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS FULL STACK PROGRAM STUDENT

 Developed PupLife - A full stack application that allows dog owners to schedule playdates. Features include authentication implemented with passport.js, MySQL Database, and an interactive search. Built utilizing these technologies: MySQL, React, Node.js, Express, and ChatKit.

2015 - PRESENT DRVO FURNITURE OWNER | OPERATOR

• Collaborate with clients to imagine, design and create iconic, artisanal furniture.

2013 - 2015 CITY OF LEE'S SUMMIT CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

- Resolved citizen's on-demand questions.
- Created, and maintained, budget tracking spreadsheets.

2012 - 2013 NOODLES & COMPANY SHIFT MANAGER

- Trained and developed new employees.
- Balanced the safe and prepared company deposits.
- Provided fast, quality service to guests.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

- Javascript
- JQuery
- React
- Node.js
- NPM
- ES6
- HTML5
- Express
- Sequelize

- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- Git
- Github
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Heroku
- Mocha
- Chai